Guide to the School of Medicine, Yale University, Financial Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Medicine, Yale University, financial records
1822-1958
RU 451
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
The records consist of the general account records of student fees and medical supplies; receipts and ledgers; and two account books of Herbert E. Smith, dean of the Yale School of Medicine.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-A (YRG 27-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of the general account records of student fees and medical supplies; receipts and ledgers; and two account books of Herbert E. Smith, dean of the Yale School of Medicine.
Medical colleges; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Smith, Herbert E. (Herbert Eugene), 1857-1933; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Financial Records, 1832-1890; Accession 1936-A-001
  - Promissory notes, 1830s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Promissory notes, 1840s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Promissory notes, 1850s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Promissory notes, 1860s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Promissory notes, 1870s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence re note, 1871
  - Correspondence re unpaid promissory note of 1871, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Account books, 1892-1893; Accession 1939-A-002
  - Three account books. The Yale Infirmary in account with:
    - L.D. Chidsey, Purveyor, 1 Church Street, New Haven (Box 1)
    - L.C. Pfaff & Son, Prime Meats, 7 and 9 Church Street, New Haven (Box 1)
    - A. Foote & Co., Fish, 353 State Street, New Haven (Box 1)
- Account books, 1897-1910; Accession 1940-A-002
  - 2 Account books. Herbert E. Smith Dean--in account with the Treasurer of Yale University, 1897-1903, 1903-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Financial Records, 1838-1958; Accession 1981-A-025
  - Student fee book: also contains account book, Dean's general, 1838-1850, 1863-1869 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Account book: Private School (at Yale), 1865-1871
  - Student fee book, 1896-1903 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Account book; Dean's, general, 1869-1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Account book; Dean's, professors and students, 1838-1870 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Account book; Dean's, professors and students, 1872-1880 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Account book; departmental and general expenses, 1881-1892 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Account book; departmental and general expenses, 1892-1909 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Account book; departmental and general expenses, 1909-1913 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Account book; departmental and general expenses, 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Account book; photography department, 1941-1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clinical Service Fees, 1933-1941 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Order Book; drugs and medical supplies, 1873-1874 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Receipts and Ledgers (miscellaneous), 1858-1864 (Box 2, Folder 13)